Next, we are going to turn this dress into a rabbit girl's dress on the basis of this neckline dress.
First, we find the 3D drawing tool, which is the 3D panel tool.
Then we can follow the sketch of the virtual model chest.
Here we can switch to a semi-transparent surface,
and then draw a curve along the middle.
Start from the center,
then press the CTRL key to create a curve point,
and then go to the side of this Shen Dao position.
Double click to finish.
Here, in order to make it easier for me to cut, I directly connected to the Shen Dao point.
If you feel that the virtual model has a material that does not look clear during the process,
you can switch to a black and white surface.
Now, because this edge is from one panel line to another panel line,
we can directly use the tool to cut along this 3D line.
Because it has a symmetrical relationship,
we can select the cut below the symmetrical column,
so that it can automatically cut in a symmetrical way.
Then we can delete the excess panels.
As for the back panel,
because we will directly pull a horizontal line from the bottom of the page,
we need to move this Shen Dao point down a little bit,
so that it does not affect the cut line.
After moving the Shen Dao point,
we can simulate the application change.
Then use the internal multilinear line tool to start from the bottom of the page.
Double click to finish.
Then go to the middle of the back panel line,
double click to finish.
Then you can use the edit panel tool to select this internal line,
right-click to select the cut,
and then delete the excess part.
But because there is no constraint on the top panel now,
it may have some volume on the whole.
Then we need to adjust the panel again.
First, we can put the point on the side in a little bit,
now it is in a relatively tight state.
Then we will see that the front panel is now loose,
it seems that the virtual model is not attached enough,
so we have to modify the front panel as well.
First, we can try to raise this panel as much as possible in the state of opening simulation,
so that the friction between the panel and the virtual model
can be fixed.
Then we will adjust it again according to this effect.
First, we have to turn the line to the vertical direction,
so that it looks like a whole cut line.
So next we use the internal multilinear line tool,
from the point of the cut on the chest,
start to go up,
vertical direction,
press Shift to double click,
finish to create a vertical line,
then choose to cut the seam line,
because we want to keep its seam line.
Now we separate this small triangle panel,
we can merge the two ends of the previous seam line.
After merging,
we can see that if there are two points here,
we will move one of them to the other near the line point,
and then convert one of them to the curve point.
I am looking at the point which was circled in my video.
We will see from here that
the chest has not been well fitted with the virtual model's chest shape.
If we move the point directly to adjust the width of this groove,
it will definitely affect the entire curve line,
so we use the additional part division tool
to make a cut in between,
so that we will not affect this part when we adjust it.
Then press the Ctrl key to move a small section along the curve
Now we can see that the chest can be very well attached to the virtual model
In the video, there are some obvious excesses in the position I marked, so we can adjust a little more manually
After opening the model, if the clothes fall down, we will drag the board manually in the state of opening the model, so that the fabric can hang on the virtual model
When we change our view to the side view, we will find that the curve on the side is not related
This is because the front is a sharp corner, and the back is also a sharp corner
If they are put together, they cannot form a flat corner
So now we need to adjust the back or front
First, use the editor tool to drag this curve to make the corner on the side of this curve close to 90 degrees
Then we go to the side view
Then adjust the back
According to the 3D window, we will see that its back is a little bit down
So we move the back point up a little bit
Now the whole back looks a little flat
Next, we can use the editor tool to slightly adjust this side a little bit
Now look from the side, its curve is connected
And this curve looks a little bit flatter
This is because the front of the model is not connected to each other
So we need to adjust it
First, we draw an internal line and cut it in the middle
Use the internal multidirectional line tool to connect these two lines
Then use the editor to right-click and select cut
After we cut it, because we just simulated it
There are some creases here
In fact, it means that there are a lot of them here
So we can separate these two lines a little bit
Then open the simulation
Then we can use the line sewing tool to sew the two sides together
After opening the simulation
When we manually adjust its wearing position
We will find that along the sewing line
There will be some wave-shaped creases
The reason for this creasing is because
We just have two shunt points on the chest here
The shunt point is a straight line point
This also causes it not to be as flexible as the curve
So here we are going to click and drag these two straight lines
To make their transition into a smooth transition
In addition to the two points above
These two points below can also be further smoothed
We can see in the 3D window
When we go to the original painting this angle
In fact, we will remove a small part of the board
In addition, the sewing line where the cut line is located
We have to delete it
Because these straight lines
We have already changed it
So it is very likely that the length is not right
So we have to use the free sewing tool
Sew the two sides together
So that the gap between them
It will gradually distribute evenly on this line
Now we will see that
The entire curve is very natural
Very even
Before we were in the top of the board
There is a little bit of inconsistencies in the state of the body
What about now?
Because we have cut in the middle
So you can make a small cut here in the middle of the cut line
Don't let it affect it
Then we will adjust a small section of the top alone
In the process of our adjustment
Now there are some other problems to be solved
One is that we now have wrinkles on both sides of the line
First of all, we can pull the point at the bottom of the line down a little
Make this line longer
The longer the line
The softer the side of it
These wrinkles will be smoother
Because now the overall strength of the whole
From the shoulder to the board before
Become the chest to the board
So we have some wrinkles on the board under the chest
What we are going to do now is to repair this wrinkle
First of all, we can widen the cut
To make his waist tighter
When we adjust the cut
Don't just adjust one side
We can see
If you only adjust one side
One is our cutting line
Will be very obvious to one side
There is another point
Is that it will not match the length of the left and right
So when we move
Be sure to pay attention
For example, the point on the left moves 10 mm to the left
The point on the right also moves 10 mm to the right
After we move the point
We can see that the whole waist is very tight now
Because he is now
It has already shown the curve of the human body
Then what we are going to change now
There is only a small section of the lower chest
So we find the two straight points of the lower chest
Move it a little to the outside of the board
Reduce the amount of material in the lower chest
Then we drag the chest board up a little
In this way, in the vertical direction
We have no wrinkles after opening the model
At this time
Although we look at it with our own eyes
This one is very tight
But we open the hard drawing
After the hard drawing
Will find
In fact, the tightest place is only the two sides of the waist
And the middle position of the chest
This is what we want
A more ideal form
Next, we are going to start
Do the pants part of the rabbit girl
Because the clothes of the rabbit girl
Usually the bottom will be sewed together
Pants form
So here we need to
Make a cut on the board
First of all, find the 3D panel tool
We are going to draw the cut line on the panel
When drawing the cut line
Press Alt4 to open the transparency chart
Then we can draw according to the model's body curve
In the drawing process, pay attention to the preview
Wait for the length of the foot
Then end the position double-click
After drawing, press Alt1
You can go back to the normal display
That is, the surface of the dense fabric
Then we are on the back
It is the same according to the needs to be drawn
Here I will draw according to my own
Based on my past experience
You can also remember to open
The transparency chart to create
Next, switch to the edit dot tool
Double click on one side
Then press the Shift key
You can select these two lines at the same time
After selecting, right-click
Then select the bottom of the symmetrical menu bar
Select cut
So that we have another time
It will automatically align and modify
Then delete the excess panels
Open the simulation
Use the edit
After the edit is used
We are going to start sewing
The part just cut
First we can use the line sewing tool
Sew the front and back together
Note that the mouse
If it is the other side
The front and back are also relative
If it is not sewn in the 2D window
If it is not sewn in
You can use the line sewing tool in the 3D window
Then pay attention to the position of the mouse
If the front is aligned with the front
Then when you click here in the back
You have to click near the back center
Open the sewing and pause
When we created the sewing line just now
You will see that the front and the back bottom
Here is not right
So now we are going to use the edit sheet tool
Select the bottom plate of the front
Remember its length
Then to the right of the back
Choose change length
And enter the value we measured just now
Then pay attention to the direction
It is tilted to the side from the back
Then open the simulation
And manually drag the chest
It's okay
Next we are going to continue
Complete the division line here in the front
Because now the division line
Is not cut to the bottom
So now we need to
Draw an internal line
So now switch to the internal line tool
Click from the bottom of the line
Then press the Shift key
In the vertical direction
Double click on the panel line
After that, use the edit sheet tool
Select this line
Right click
Select cut and sew
Then we are going to use the circular curve tool
Click and drag
This angle straight line on both sides
Let it form a circular curve
Because we don't have it now
Adjust the friction coefficient of the panel
So it's like real cloth
Very easy to slide
To prevent the clothes from sliding
We can put on the clothes
Press and hold the button
Press and hold the W key
Single machine panel
Can create a fixed pin on the panel
After selecting the fixed pin
Right click
Can fix the fixed pin to the virtual model
When the fixed pin
Fix the clothes to the virtual model
After that
The top of the grid of the clothes
Will be fixed
On the top of the grid of the virtual model
So unless the virtual model
The action has changed
Otherwise it won't affect